Soccer City in Johannesburg in Sunday's
FIFA World Cup final but who will they
play attention here turns to Germany and
Spain the European Champions who meet in
the second semi-final at the Magnificent
Moses mabidia stadium in Durban
Germany's only problem has been her to
play in the absence of the suspended
Thomas Mueller Kakao still has an
abdominal problem Toni Cruz who might
have played has a virus sir piota
trakovsky who has been a late substitute
in the last three matches gets his first
start of the tournament here tonight
closer as ever as the lone Striker it
remains that 4-2 3-1 formation for yakim
Lev site
and it has been a successful formation
too hasn't it
they have been pouring goals in the game
so far
my referee tonight is um taking charge
of his fourth match at these World Cup
finals Victor kassai from Hungary he's
produced the yellow card on nine
occasions Brazil against the Korean DPR
Mexico Uruguay and USA against Ghana his
three previous games and it's unlikely
he'll get the final now unprecedented
that a semi-final referee does get the
final Fernando Torres that's the big
name missing misfired all tournament
he's left on the bench so it's Pedro
Rodriguez who takes his place in the 11
after three substitute appearances in
the five previous games so David beer
with five goals to his name will push up
as the out and out front man for Spain
tonight
he remains their talisman
in love 50 years of age the German coach
his contract is up at this the end of
This World Cup so Victory here tonight
might do his chances of a renegotiation
no harm at all and Vincente Del Bosque
the man on the other side the former
Real Madrid coach
and it could be anything tonight Germany
have ripped up The Stereotype in ripping
through this competition it's been Spain
who have been the more pragmatic but
this is a game that promises goals and
bags of entertainment here tonight
with the Ultimate Prize at stake a place
in the World Cup final itself against
the Dutch
spedolski who's trying to make progress
on this near side and an only problem
here too
for busquets who just Twisted away from
The Challenge
but he's okay he's gonna be able to run
it off
so here's Sergio Ramos
Spain looking to settle into that
passing pattern of theirs it's been
building some quarters as a Revenge
mission for Germany tonight after the
European final two years ago which was
won by Spain by just the one girl to nil
it's been dismissed by yakim love who
says it's a very different team his side
are putting out tonight
much younger
and much more ambition in terms of going
forward
but early cagey stuff from the Spanish
Ramos looking for it but it's Podolski
gets the head up
will be a Spanish throw
in fact six players from either side who
um do survive that European Final in
Vienna
in 2008
so they know each other very very well
here
's busquets
busquets again it's a very quiet opening
PK
it's Petra who's laying it left and
captivir is the man who's in support and
via's in the middle but it's over here
and easily uh in fact it might go up for
a throw and just just go for a girl kick
for the Germans
so a kg start
Islam
and it's taken over the captaincy and
see insist that he's going to keep hold
of it if he can despite the return at
some point of Michael Ballack
have a phenomenal record at this stage
of tournaments to the Germans their 17th
World Cup they've won it of course on
three occasions runners-up on four
11 semi-finals they've won six of them
[Music]
so they know their way through these um
highly tense situations
but it is being played at walking pace
in these early stages
here's any Esther
forward by uh PK
it's a nice touch by Pedro
Chevy here's an ester again
lunge of a challenge from kadira
but they have a bit of width here now
it's Petro
[Applause]
Russell's done well to win it back for
the Germans
and we just have a bit of a problem on
the pitch at the moment as you perhaps
might be able to see
[Applause]
the idiots are being taken away
and that's the last he'll see of this
World Cup semi-final
so he's very patient start from both
sides here just a little stuttering at
the moment
we might have expected this from the
Spanish but the Germans just being
forced to play at their Pace just at
this stage
kadira
matasaka looking wide for Philip Lam
B close-up who's had an outstanding
tournament
really has come as a surprise for all of
those who's watched his um
his Club form of the last couple of
years
he and Podolski have been very ordinary
playing for their respective clubs but
in German colors have been
prolific
here's PK
but dolski is the man on the chase but
can't prevent the ball back safely
towards Cassius
his busquets
well it is going to get Lively up that's
the anticipation anyway as this match
wears on
five minutes played and um very little
of any relevance produced by either side
so far
other than that the Spanish are enjoying
the possession that um they do love to
enjoy here's Pedro
it's good by Pedro but it was equally
outstanding by Philip lamp
doing his defensive duties well enough
Chevy
it's PK
little bit of movement ahead of him for
PK here including um
that of Pedro has been the liveliest
player on the pitch so far and slowing
it in for beer
well well watched by Neuer because via
just got ahead of the defense there
and a first real chance of the night
being on the end a bit but it was Petros
ball through
absolutely inch perfect here and fear
reading it well
Moya just getting in with a blocking
challenge
PK
Schweinsteiger
he's done well to write a couple of
challenges and take the Germans forward
with some positivity for the first time
in this game looking for closer in the
middle but almost inevitably Puyol is
there to block it away and captivea
shipping it to the relative safety of
the German half
lamb
Pedro
and here's Iniesta
again looking for that slide reel ball
through for Veer but murtasaka there
the murder sucker again and here's boy
tank as the Germans look to shake the
shackles here but not with passing like
that from Mesut Ozil
[Applause]
they have been a phenomenon that these
World Cup finals the Germans they came
into it with a reputation of a side that
was still being rebuilt but are getting
close to the final product here
but they're being tested at the back now
as Ramos as it is won't
Bring It Forward and now Pedro and yes
there's clear on that left-hand side but
the direct ball was look for
I'm poor thing just tickling it out of
play for the Spanish throw
three times they've scored four goals
in matches thus far the Germans not
since Brazil in 1970 as a side managed
to do that
and we all know the reputation of that
Brazilian side that has been carried
down the ages
his busquets
no Ramos
giving nothing away
Petro
Schweinsteiger looking long for the Run
of closer but PK
always has his measure though some
defending to do here well it looks as
though the gun out of play but a glance
from the referee to his assistant on the
far side says otherwise and closer
very nearly closing down the goalkeeper
Schweinsteiger
Germans with a chance to pass here but
the flag up on the far side against Ozil
and the first half chance for the
Germans to break is thwarted
there
it's Chevy
no Sergio Ramos
not too many in the middle
providing something to aim for so work
left again
Iniesta
they certainly are a patient side to
Spanish quite happy to sit with a ball
at their feet for as long as it takes
Iniesta
here's Ramos again now
I'm just crunching it into the back of
Lucas Podolski together Spanish throw
[Applause]
me Alonso
that's a sucker just but here's Iniesta
a little skipping run of his but
not able to find a way through but just
beginning to threaten that
[Music]
though it's then gets the throat
well it was tight wasn't it but um Erza
looked as though he might just have been
maybe in line with that last line of
defense but either way
referee's assistant on the far side had
the final word
lamb
there's Captiva Ramos
[Applause]
foreign
the most prolific passes in the World
Cup as well
both sides have a real educated Style
Shelby Alonso Sergio Ramos has already
taken up his position down this right
hand flank and bertang careful but has
conceded the corner
it's the first of the night
so a chance here for the
Spanish
big man to get up there around also
loves to have a fling at Corners Puyol
and PK
making their slowly measured walks up to
and a test here for Manuel Neuer
andiesta back to Chevy
still a crowded penalty area Chevy
Alonso here's any Esther again Little
Triangle of passes and driven it and
pull you all
well it came to him at a flash
and he did well to get his head on to it
speed it was driven in by Iniesta
just steering it over
when it could so easily have been the
opener from Carlos Puyol
there's kadira
[Music]
this is poeting
[Applause]
love hasn't had too much
to be encouraged by from his side so far
it has been Spain who dominate matters
here with 70 of possession in the
opening 14 minutes they haven't done an
awful lot with it but they have produced
the two best chances of the game so far
[Applause]
foreign
just denied possession here
Chevy Iniesta
militasaka was looming large
[Music]
Islam
drakovsky
and PK will have to concede a corner
here
so the Germans having been under
pressure
now have a chance themselves to launch
something here inside this Spanish
penalty area
to tease one in here on the left foot
well the goalkeeper came and just got
fingertips to that
there were two behind him but um
Ika Casillas just about did enough here
foreign
Steiger and Friedrich
in anticipation
but Cassius the man who took it away
from the but the Germans have a second
opportunity
a little more positive this time from
Casius
but Burton has it back
here's tokovsky
and over here for the goal kick
so now is taking his opportunity tonight
and the absence of Mueller who suspended
of course
in all likelihood if Germany do make the
final Muller will be back and um in the
starting 11 but
chance for trakovsky maybe to catch his
Coach's Eye
herself
just fine snig up
this is kadira
and a rare chance for the Germans to
enjoy a moment or two with a ball at
their feet but not for long though they
do have a throw
what time to take
and they'll have another opportunity
here
it's going to go long this time with the
arch of the back and a fling to the
middle over the head of kadira headed
Away by PK
here's mirtasaka
Schweinsteiger
and Captiva with a chance to
send it further clear
it's a Germany throw
first semi-final for the Spanish and
World Cup history their 13th World Cup
they've managed to reach quarterfinals
on four previous occasions
but never further than this never this
far
and in terms of possession at least they
are dominating things in the early
stages of this game
is busquets
one of several in this Spanish side here
playing with or will be next season
playing with Barcelona
motorcycle chipping away
Alonso
so Sergio busquets
Petra
napuyol
it's exactly how Spain want to play this
Captiva
shabby Alonso again has a look up and
sees that Sergio Ramos has made a
terrific run down this right hand side
his touch is excellent too and the
strike for girl wasn't wide by much
it's always asking a little too much
maybe of Sergio Ramos from that angle
but he gave himself the opportunity
there's the man who's having to watch
tonight Thomas Muller suspended
foreign
a few games along the way that the
Germans have come out second best in
terms of possession but
their counter-attacking abilities what
has seen them through
their Flair and style when going forward
but they haven't been given many pieces
so far here tonight
it's captivir Iniesta
no shabby the man has made more passes
at this tournament than anyone else
in that role as Kingpin in Midfield it's
snapped away for Petra but it's a Sakura
cross to tidy things up and clear it
away and the Germans looking to get it
forward if they can but busquet steps in
another shabby Alonso it's Iniesta this
time is clear on the left but
the shorter and it would seem or simple
ball with some aimed towards Petra but
unable to do anything with it
foreign
Sergio Ramos
it's an extraordinary amount of
possession the Spanish have had here so
far
see five percent now with just over 21
minutes played really is being played at
their Pace here
and yes they're on the overlap
Pedro and fear in the middle
and the corner kick conceded from The
Challenge from Sami kadira
so they're under the cost you can hear
the Germans
[Music]
it's all about turning possession into
goals
which the Spanish haven't always been
great at in this tournament
Shelby Alonso with a ball in motorcycle
with a header away here's closer
and now here comes the counter-attack
or at least it would have been with a
tidier ball from Lucas but all scale the
closer given a sniff of an opportunity
it's Petro
Chevy
and again very nearly a telling ball had
it not been for pair motorcycle
Podolski
closer in the middle
and he has support too he tried to turn
and turns into the way of Carlos Puyol
it'll be Mighty relief to steer that
back to his goalkeeper but
just a half chance Brewing there for the
Germans
Chevy
Pedro
they're giving only rare glimpses of
possession here though the Germans and
Spain back into their holding pattern
again as Iniesta
Looms
shall be Alonso
captivio is offside
just straight by a yard or two the left
back
well this is going to be tight isn't it
and it looks as though captive here was
actually on side it might have been via
who was offside when the ball was played
the referee's assistant on this near
side might just have had his view
blocked and saw the redshirted veer
maybe just assume that captive ear was
ahead of him
[Music]
kadira
only as far as Puyol and now busquets
and Chevy and quick as you like the
Spanish are
back on the offensive here with Pedro
via
he's being well marshaled and just as
well locked by Friedrich and cleared
Away by boat
Chevy
Iniesta
here's Ramos now again offering that
threat on the right hand side of Burton
doing just enough Ramos is claiming but
the referee and his assistant are in
accordance there's no foul
Iniesta
Ramos again offering the width Veer in
the middle Pedro in the middle it's uh
Pedro it's aimed for and for something
on the spectacular side
but his Miss hit chip Landing safely in
the hands of Manuel Neuer
but they remain a threat
and there was the acclaimed foul by
Sergio Ramos he might just have been
clipped by waiting
Schweinsteiger
foreign
really has grown into the role of
Captain one or two doubting his maturity
when the tournament began whether he was
Captain's material but
he has proven himself to be up to the
task
isn't he asked up
Sergio Ramos
[Applause]
we're happy to keep it at a simple Pace
here
busquets
[Music]
well there's no sign the pattern
changing thus far is there
Spain playing a very high level
technical game here
no rush no dash it's all about keeping
possession
suddenly up in the tempo for busquets
but
Sherman his defense was back to cover
the foot in from Sergio Ramos which is
why the Germans have the free kick here
to
just relieve a little bit of pressure
and there's a problem here too
which will be causing some concern on
the German bench
love just um
looking here because the Lucas Podolski
has gone down and he's obviously in some
discomfort he's managed to pick himself
up again since foreign on
[Music]
should be okay
this closer
this is kadira
[Music]
Philip lamb
padoski is back on the pitch by the way
Justin
ambling on this near side
Schweinsteiger
[Music]
Anna Friedrich
he has given it away
can do little with it
and Germany have a chance to bring it
now
plenty of Spanish Defenders back here
erzl chipping in towards closer but
not quite the pass required
and the Spanish have the goal kick
[Music]
that's one for the purist here tonight
quite the cut and thrust that we maybe
imagined before the game began
Iniesta
Sergio Ramos
Chevy always looking to create if he can
can't see a way forward so here's Shelby
Alonso from a long way out but just why
well they've um
produced the shot so far tonight the
Spanish
fourth of the night only one though has
been on target thus far
but it's more than the Germans have been
able to produce with their lack of
possession
foreign
with a chance to break
poor ball uncharacteristically poor ball
as well from David Veer just behind
Petra
Schweinsteiger nothing away with Ramos
it's a battle at the Spanish of one
and they will have a throw here as well
30 minutes played and still no score of
the Durban Stadium
in this very tight and very tense
semi-final
it is Spain who have dominated Who
provided the better of the chances and
the half chances
and they who have utterly dominated
possession so far
this veer
closer
Tchaikovsky
and Philip lamb
ursul's made a little run ahead of him
it's Square to trochowsky he'll have a
go on the left foot and Casillas had to
get down to make a very smart save
well he would have been disappointed had
that sneaked in and his left hand
upright but even so it
needed his total concentration and he
just got a hand to that as well Ika
Casillas
the German supporters heartened as their
side produced their first real effort on
girl here tonight
and a corner kick to boot
cushioned Away by puyon
it's a game that's like a real heavy
thunderstorm on a summer's day you can
feel the intensity and the
the pressure of it and every now and
again just the old flash of lightning
seventy thousand though haven't been off
their seats too often in this game so
far
here's Pedro
Spain looking to work it again
Chevy
motor sack has had that little Channel
blocked all night so far
but it's only going to take one ball to
beat him
[Music]
it's a German throw
schwein snig up
buy a tank
carefully and cautiously up to Podolski
kadira but don't ski ahead of him kadera
looks to the center sees the universal
close has broken away at the back but
ursul can't get it past Carlos puyo
largest ever blocking it away but it is
a corner
so the pressure beginning to melt now
the German's way
just having a little more of this game
Tchaikovsky's ball in and Casillas
[Applause]
calming it to relative safety
[Music]
see us again with a diving punch here's
Pedro
via wanted it played early he was free
on this right-hand side you can see him
flapping his arms he's in acres of space
and when they finally try to work over
over to him the um the ball is simply
not good enough
but for that um early pass to be played
David veer
foreign
off he goes with one of those silky
little runs of his and looking to slide
it in for Via
okay
he's Bulletin
Friedrich
A little sloppy from the Germans has
some given rather cheap possession back
Spanish way
helping to win it back
Islam
well both coaches yesterday at the press
conferences were talking about the
amount of running that both sides would
have to do
and they have covered some distance but
not at Great Pace but now at quickens
here's Podolski offside
[Applause]
and just waiting and watchful just
looking to draw their opponents
into uh some kind of wrong-footedness in
defense when they have the ball at the
feet either side especially the Spanish
foreign
just wanders out of position before
their pants and
maybe they thought they'd seen it there
the Germans but Podolski was offside
Chevy
captivir pushing forward into space
it's Iniesta
fear again making a tentative little
darts ahead of him but Iniesta holds it
up not good enough
wants more to aim for
Petra
the movement from the Spanish is some
really fantastic to watch making
themselves available for each other but
in the end the threads just unpicking
[Music]
love looks so reasonably relaxed at the
moment on the German bench
foreign
touch is almost impeccable but can't
quite keep hold of it now kadira Germany
looking to break Podolski bowaten's gone
on the overlap used as a foil Podolski
tried to go middle
feinsteiger
Tchaikovsky does well to keep it in has
support from Lam
here's erzl has a look
didn't fancy the angle or the distance
at the first attempt and in trying to
find a nearer range runs into trouble
[Music]
it's a game with real Sumptuous
qualities if not goal chances so far
patients from two teams one in
possession the other in defense not to
give anything away
shabby
the man who rarely loses possession but
he has on this occasion
you can see that Spain's still
dominating possession 57 percent
but they haven't hurt the Germans so far
a couple of chances but
nothing that the Germany side have not
been able to deal with
Islam
[Music]
it's a game that you know can just
explode into life at any given moment
both sides with so much potential and so
much pace
remains on the knife edge here's some
working it well to Boateng and
converting with a silky touch but Ramos
the no-nonsense defender was in his way
and he asked up
this man is on the Move Jerome Burton at
the end of this tournament
leaving Hamburg to join the English Club
Manchester City
and a free kick for Spain for the foul
on Gerard Pique
is shabby
PK
come out Touch of a central Defender
just running the man who tried to close
him down
and finding the ROM on the left-hand
side of Captiva whose One Touch puts him
in a range of the Cross murder sucker
the header away Captain is still out
there trying to trouble this German
defense alarms hacking away
it's Petro
captivates on side
and he estimates but bertang will thwart
his Ambitions with a header away
Iniesta
well he ran fair and square into the
shoulder of Jerome Burton
and he's going to get a free kick here
[Applause]
Alberto's complaining that he could do
very little about this because um
and he has to ran into him that looked
painful
see that captive ear was offside before
that ball was played across this time
missed by the assistant on the near side
but a chance here for Spain
it's a game that's been whining Tighter
and Tighter
and maybe the spring is about to be
released
Chevy's got plenty to aim for
typically Spanish they try to unpick
that German defense rather than throwing
the ball into the middle
and pool from halfway inside his
opponents half were played all the way
back to his goalkeeper
[Music]
Ramos
foreign
Petra
Captiva tight to that left touchline but
shabby Alonso goes right
would have known that Sergio Ramos would
have been there waiting for it it's hit
towards VR but murtasaka
a big fella in the way again with a
header he's been the last man on several
occasions and he's played his role well
enough so far
[Applause]
turned temporarily on the right hand
side
[Music]
just about a minute and a half of the
first 45 minutes remaining plus whatever
stoppage time is going to be added but
there can't be much
Germany will have a free kick so maybe a
chance to finish the half
on the offensive here too
[Music]
fried Friedrich
motorcycle
[Applause]
and here's via
looking to turn this into a trouble for
the German defense Pedro now
we'll take on Burton can't find the
angle finds more Defenders but still
gets the corner
[Applause]
super tech just about doing his job but
Spade
with that third corner of the night
[Music]
they're waiting on the edge of the
penalty area here the heavy artillery of
Chevy puts it in and kept them here can
only glancing away his Pedro
Struck it well enough but it's Sami
kadira
one minute of stoppage time to be at it
at the end of the 45
Germans have ridden the danger
for the time being at least
[Music]
the closest that ever so well to get
ahead of puyon he's got ursul here so
now with a Chance
well he's gone down and looks pleasantly
at the referee who gives nothing
[Applause]
well the first touch maybe should have
been a shot there from Mesut Ozil
just gave a chance for the Spanish
defense to close in
and what he thought was a foul was a
fair challenge here's captain of air
Spain with a chance to attack at the
other end
Away by motorcycle
[Music]
Petra who's gonna go for goal
solid Enough by Manuel Neuer
and a half time whistle sounds
with Germany's best chance certainly
coming right at the end of that opening
45 minutes
that have been wonderfully intense ursul
here now look at The Challenge from
Ramos
maybe he should have gone for cold
earlier
just got the back of his calves caught
by Sergio Ramos
it remains scoreless it's Germany and
Ill spay nil in the semi-final in Durban
[Music]
well no change in Personnel at the start
of this second period just wonder if
there's going to be a change of style
and already the Spanish um attacking
with a little bit of electricity Petra
making that break down that right hand
side but uh falls back instantly here's
Captiva
back inside the Spanish half they have
dominated possession utterly dominated
possession the uh the Spanish in the
game thus far
they haven't produced too many shots on
target
and that will be the slight concern it
has been the worry throughout the
tournament
here's myotech
Sergio Ramos
getting Pedro away Veer in the middle
over the head of murtasaka but likewise
over the head of vehicle
it's a real mismatch in terms of um
height between those two
six foot five inches tall per motorcycle
and Renown as a Defender who very rarely
gives
and he fouls away
historkovsky
kidera
urzel
another penalty claim towards the end of
the first half that wasn't given it's
about three German players offside at
the moment so they have to go backwards
here's berteng
close-up
kadira's up there too close is looking
for a way through here's kadira
now Tchaikovsky
trying to work it on the left foot for
the shot
into a wall of Defenders
there
Iniesta keeping his balance and keeping
his feet but giving the ball away murta
Saka nips in its Schweinsteiger
sees it closer again he's offside ahead
of him so it's a more negative ball
that's required
Anna Friedrich Brooke is um
goal scoring duck
in the last game his first International
goal in a 77 attempts
in the match against Argentina
you have been up to there in the uh
German the most capped Outfield German
player never to have scored a goal but
in that four nil ratney
finally managed to find a way through
his feinsteiger
tank
little more positive Nerf for the
Germans
closer
pool with a stretch
and Petro had a chance to bring it away
with some relish
Friedrich was a cross but missed and
Petra has beaten two Defenders now
he's beating Friedrich for a third time
Chevy Alonso
what terrific play by Pedro down that
right hand flank
can be Alonso unable to provide the
Final Touch
but Burton and Friedrich
another swinging at fresh air
as Pedro took it past them
Tchaikovsky
Tchaikovsky looked as though he might
have started from an offside position
but the uh flag remaining down
Spain of course the Iranian world
champion the reigning European Champions
but it isn't often a title that has sat
well and a side that has chased the
world Crown only once of the European
Champions actually won the world title
that was West Germany 1972 and then 1974
when they won the World Cup on home soil
here's Pedra
Sergio Ramos back to Chevy and Chevy
Alonso
well he's getting a little closer
it's the third time tonight that is um
had a pot from distance
and he's yet to force a save from Manuel
Neuer
I think it's fair to say the German
goalkeeper on that occasion wasn't
entirely sure it was going wide when the
ball left the boot
well the longer the game goes on the
more chances they're going to create
at least you would have thought
here's captivir
Iniesta
Germans are going to make a change very
soon Marcel Janssen is stripped and
ready down below us
and Germany defense I'm going to keep
its concentration here because here's
Petra again the man who has looked the
live list of characters in Spanish
colors so far tonight Schweinsteiger
looking for the art ball with Podolski
Hanson has twice come on before as a
substitute in these World Cup finals
each time when he's replaced Jerome
Burton and it looks as though the um the
same switch is about to be made here
here's Captiva
shabby
Sergio Ramos again making that run
unchecked on that right hand side
maybe that's the reason why Boateng will
be coming off soon here's Petro
[Music]
show me Alonso
doing enough here but it might be his
last
change is going to be made it is coming
off
and for the timing at least his teammate
Marcel Jansen from Hamburg the one who's
going to replace him here the Burton's
on his way to England at the the end of
these World Cup finals
I might just have played his last uh
this tournament who's to say but it's
Marcel Janson who will come on here
it's his third appearance at this world
cup he uh managed just the one four
years ago in the third and fourth
playoff game against Portugal
PK
murder sucker with a head up
Tchaikovsky
busquets
here shall be Alonso now Captiva
[Music]
foreign
there hurried
Schweinsteiger
sees the breaking four ahead of him but
it's wired to Tchaikovsky who wants it
back
just find Steiger with a challenge that
upends Iniesta which has given Spain a
free kick
[Applause]
and a first touch for Marcel yansen
fresh From the Bench here's kadira
the Anson proving an energetic Runner
down that left-hand flank
[Applause]
and he will get the free kick here too
in fact it's a throw
[Music]
Iniesta
always seems so aware of what's around
him as soon as he has the ball and
here's another of that ilch and shaving
and he asked up
badulski was the matter is trying to
track back here and he asked his picked
up Chevy via's there too here is fear
who will hit it
and again the goalkeeper not entirely
sure it was going wide and taking no
chances but
it was
they are not finding his range
it's nine shots the Spanish have
produced so far tonight but only two of
them on target
[Music]
just them leaping in to Captivate hence
the free kick
and here's PK
Spanish might not have been as fluent in
the last two or three games in these
World Cup finals as we would expect them
to have been
rather grinding their way to results
but they are still on this terrific run
of form
now beaten by Romania in November 2006
and in 53 games since then they have won
48.
the only two they have lost though have
been on South African soil against the
United States and the Confederation Cup
last year and against Switzerland this
year in the world cup and they're under
a little bit of pressure here
for all the reputation to the Spanish of
being a team that does like to score
goals they don't give many away
Schweinsteiger with a challenge that has
given the throw here
20 games 20 competitive matches under
Del Bosco now and they have only
conceded 11 goals in those 20 matches so
that um partnership at the back of PK
and Puyol with Casius just behind
has been very very effective
[Applause]
foreign
here's Pedro
captivir
nice touch from Iniesta has captive here
on his way
just behind Chevy Alonso Pedro good save
by the goalkeeper
still not away
it's Iniesta
from the tightest of idols and fear was
inches away from turning it in
it's the closest they've got
and there might be more to come here
here's Sergio Ramos
Germany defending desperately at the
moment
Chevy
Chevy again
Petro
on just wide
well the plunge by Neuer but it was
always going wide of his upright so
they've survived that little spell of
pressure here
there was a final fling
but what came before was a little more
frightening lovely back here Iniesta in
his stride and here lunging
just unable to turn it in
and then the shot superbly saved by
Neuer
and they were expecting that to go in
one way or another
stays at nil nil
and it remains in the balance
11 shots now for Spain
three of them on target
Iniesta
via
cutting in as he loves to do
bumped Away by Tchaikovsky
lamb claims for a handball
Schweinsteiger
[Applause]
let's put all skate
Jansen
and PK
sweeping it out for a throw
sides of the game is just opening up a
bit now
with very nearly an hour played
closer it was always a difficult ask
wasn't it from that kind of an angle
the ball deflected him off a Spanish
Head
did his best but um always unlikely to
keep it down under the circumstances
he's a man on a missile of course
one more girl equals him as the uh
world record World Cup goal scorer
Chevy
[Applause]
oh here's Captiva
Friedrich heading back
still danger Petro turning it out
towards Ramos
good challenge for Janssen the Germans
are about to make another change here as
well
I guess trukovsky is going to come off
and Tony Cruz who's coming on
well there was a suggestion that Chris
was the preferred starter here tonight
but
foreign
but with less than half an hour to play
Cruz is going to be risked here
Tchaikovsky the man who gives away
and said a terrific season Tony Cruz on
learn it by a Leverkusen headed back
with Bayern Munich next year
shabby Alonso
Chevy
Iniesta
Sergio Ramos has made the rally to the
area
and claims he was tripped as he went
[Applause]
well there seemed to be contact between
Podolski and Ramos
but it was an electrifying run here
picked her superbly well by Chevy Alonso
it's wonderful football All Around by
the Spanish
and I don't think there was contact was
there
Islam
Spanish free kick
foreign
just signs
in the last few minutes
that the Spanish could engineer a breach
in this German defense
what have they got here shabi Alonso
flicking it in
easily Away by murder second
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
space again shabby
looking to grind this Germany fence down
severe
Chevy
Alonso here's Iniesta
into curling and again but overheating
[Applause]
foreign
still not hurting the Germans
still not finding a way through
and as time Ticks by
25 minutes left to play
an extra hint of desperation might just
begin to creep in
foreign
again just having the Germans chasing
Shadows for the moment
captive here
Iniesta having a look before he collects
knowing where he's going to play it but
um not quite working out how he planned
it
and Neuer with a big boot downfield
Janssen
willing again to take on the uh Spanish
on the outside
he's left a bit of space here as well he
had some of that forward Dash is via
a kadira
this is urzel
Chevy Spain
looking to raise the level of threat if
they can
Iniesta
second
here's beer
pulling wide
and going for the near post but again a
very safe Pair of Hands provided by
Emmanuel
there's not done much wrong here tonight
foreign
relentless
way more attack from the Spanish
continues to pound on the German Shores
and they have a free kick here too
[Applause]
he's good at winning those isn't he
Andres Iniesta
you get the feeling he knew what he was
doing
slip by Pedro just offering the Germans
the opportunity to bring it away khadira
asking a little too much of Cruz but
Falls fortuitously for Schweinsteiger
this is Marcel Janssen
who has it again now Podolski
result
space here for Podolski and the shot is
beaten away Tony Cruz found a position
and for all the pressure they've been
under suddenly they found the counter
and look how much space Cruise had there
[Applause]
and a German free kick
to give them extra heart
after the potential blow they almost
delivered a moment ago
podolsky's ball over and close
finding Casillas in his way as he often
is
so now it's Del bosque's turn to worry a
little as his side find themselves Under
Pressure here
still we await the Breakthrough
closest has come as close as anybody so
far
PK with the header away
lamp
grosser again
the header from murtasaka who was still
up there and threatening it came last
off a Spanish Defender so it will be
another corner here
[Applause]
[Music]
PK it was who just got the touch
[Applause]
are looking to swing this one over again
now what can Germany do from here
they haven't had many sustained periods
of pressure and possession inside their
opponent's half
[Applause]
now they do have the chance here to ask
a few questions of this Spanish defense
his motorcycle
[Applause]
gross
winiesta just nipping in
our four German Defenders back so it was
asking an awful lot of it to make
anything of that which you can't do and
she finds Tiger's ball towards closer
but
to see us with a safe catch
and he has to have done it again
one is signed another free kick
knew the change was coming and you there
was very little on for him and even if
the um the ball were in person heated so
having won the free kick Spain with beer
a little stumble but that's around us
[Applause]
here's an Esther
four in the middle Iniesta with a quick
feet
but Schweinsteiger with a timely
challenge
[Music]
still impossible to pick a winner with
any certainty at this stage but it is
Spain who just have the advantage here
Chavez corner
and it's the man from the back
who has given Spain the lead
curlers
flying in
the German defense could only look at
each other
one might be enough
[Applause]
and with 73 minutes playing
it is Carlos puyo
who has given them the platform
[Applause]
well Puyol and PK were fighting amongst
themselves there to get the header first
but puyo was absolutely determined
flung himself at it
nobody picked him up
and absolutely nothing that Manuel Neuer
could do about that
so Spain have their breakthrough
and Germany have 60 Minutes in which to
respond
[Applause]
they've only been behind once in this
tournament so far Germany
and they stayed behind to the very end
when they lost one nil to Serbia
but tonight
they have to fight back if they are
going to make that dream of a World Cup
final
and for all the fancy stuff that spainer
produced tonight with a ball playing
midfielders and the forwards have run
and run
it's the no-nonsense approach from the
central Defender that has given them the
Breakthrough
[Applause]
how did Germany respond here
's kadira
it's Janssen
[Music]
it's Podolski
Schweinsteiger has to go Square
murtasaka trying to push forward but it
has to go back to Friedrich
foreign
maybe a little too far for a direct
strike at goal it is crucial in fact
who's going to take responsibility here
little chip towards uh closer but could
see us again had it read well enough
and Spain with a chance to catch her
again here's fear
three German Defenders back he has
beaten one of them not the second
Ursa with a challenge
Away by Neuer
[Music]
and at least a couple offside of it um
still a job to do here for Friedrich
it's only the third goal of the entire
tournament that the Germans have
conceded as well
Serbia scoring in their win against them
in England getting one in consolation in
the four one defeat apart from that
they have kept clean sheets
and they'll have a corner
so spaying it up can see many either
all they have to do is
keep them out for what remains 13
minutes to play but there'll be a test
here
Cruiser hit it over matasaka going in
so Ramos who got his head to it first
Cruz again
this time PK
[Applause]
No Way Forward at the moment for the
Germans
despite their best intentions it has to
go all the way back to Manuel Neuer
kadira
closer
but they're not able to keep possession
here
it's not being allowed to settle
kedera
Islam
just about keeping it in play and a
decent ball over two which uh PK dealt
with but Ozil
murtasaka a little agricultural in the
delivery
who you'll miss with a header ursul
ated
swung Away by Petro Here Comes fear he's
only got one Defender to beat here it's
Friedrich via murtasaka appearing
now the chance just disappears
but it is certainly opening up now
Germans having to commit more men
forward
you're gonna make a third change as well
very shortly Mario Gomez is a prime for
Action down in the technical area
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
Ando Torres is going to be coming on for
Spain as well
[Applause]
that's going to be a very positive
change by Vincente Del Bosque
there's Janssen
always done well he's found a bit of
space
but he's also found PK with a cross
so here come the changes
and it's going to be kadira who's coming
off for the Germans Mario Gomez who will
take his place
Super Mario the man they call him from
Bayern Munich
and uh Fernando Torres
who has been misfiring for the
tournament so far he's gonna come on in
place of David via
for Spain don't forget that Del Bosque
still has a couple of changes up his
sleeve as well should he require this is
the first substitution of the night here
David Vega in the heroes reception for
once it was not him that needed to break
the deadlock
[Music]
spanner fan Another Hero tonight in the
shape of Carlos Puyol
[Applause]
and you wonder if you sense that um
incented El Bosque feels this might be a
night for Fernando Torres to finally
find his touch
nine minutes of a semi-final to play
Spain leading by one goal to nil
it's far from over yet
here's Janssen with a decent delivery
Gomez trying to get on the end of that
Lam
B it's a Chevy it's a lot of space up
ahead of him here and a chance now for
Pedro Pedro to finish it
he's got Fernando Torres there too oh
well they try to do too much
Fernando Torres was begging for the pass
and the young Pedro sensing absolute
Glory
well they made a mess of it in the end
so Germany still have a Lifeline here's
herzl lamb
you just wonder how much Pedro is going
to rule that missed opportunity too in
these dying moments because Spain
certainly had an opportunity there an
apology to Fernando Torres because he
knows how good a chance this was
trying to take on Friedrich
when tolles on his inside was completely
unmarked but there was the goal
Carlos Puyol
with a terrific header
Away by PK
Islam
seven minutes to play plus whatever stop
his time is going to be added murtasaka
at least if it stays this way
one girl would take us into extra time
if it was scored by the Germans
foreign
well it looked like a good challenge
from Shelby Alonso
complaints to the referee have earned
him an extra ticking off
but another opportunity here
he's having a good look at this
little chip by him but puyo with the
header away it's feinsteiger
we're almost with a head up
Schweinsteiger oh he's found a shooting
position Puyol was looking around at his
teammates
after making the challenge as if to say
how on Earth was he given that
opportunity lamb
Schweinsteiger well he's gone down the
referee sees nothing
there's a cluster of appeals on in fact
he has given the free kick as he know he
has and it is a throw
and another change
for the Spanish here
David Silva who we haven't seen for the
opening since the opening game is going
to come on
[Applause]
and Pedro
is taken off well perhaps a little
punishment for the opportunity he
spurned earlier when he really should
have sealed it for the Spanish or at
least set up the chance for Fernando
Torres to seal it
instead a little subdue to his
substituted
and David
Silva who was um a Mainstay in the
European Championship win two years ago
but we haven't seen much of him at this
tournament is the man who comes on
Chevy hitting it launch of Fernando
Torres but the goalkeeper's always
favorite
shove it
it's rather a forlorn pursuit of that by
mirislav close-up
Spain never before in a World Cup final
find themselves now only four minutes
away
the team that has been the great
Underachievers on the world stage over
the years
Islam with a ball in just over the head
of close-up we are with a header
Spain against surviving but there are
one or two hairy moments developing
but as Germany push everybody forward
they're prone to the counter Tony is
just trying to roll it in for silver
[Applause]
foreign
faces of desperation now those German
players
it's slipping through their fingers
lamb
who y'all
it's the big boot away and anywhere
we'll do
just to put the Germans back inside
their own half two and a half minutes to
play just under
yakum love knows it is getting
desperately close to the exit door now
Janssen goes long
Gomez beaten in the air
Iniesta Here Comes Torres
what a time for him to find his goal
scoring touch if he can
he's going to take him on and it took
some fine defending from Friedrich in
the end to deny in the shooting position
but a Spanish corner
[Music]
foreign
they have waited decades for this moment
and now they're only seconds away
Spain holding the ball and holding their
Nerf
Chevy in
Silver's Force wide
Iniesta again Chevy's in acres of space
in the middle little chip towards silver
Iniesta lucky to gather it in just
bouncing off the knees of motorcycle
and it will be another Spanish corner
kick and if nothing else it winds the
clock down
foreign
so many theories offered as to why Spain
have
never matched their talents with
trophies
the divisions within the country of so
many different regions with their strong
identities
Here Comes Silva
happy to take the corner kick
[Applause]
but over the last few years they have
become Unified
United by one common cause and that is
to chase the glory
we won the European title two years ago
and now they're getting very very close
to contesting the world Crown against
the Dutch
three minutes still to play
so there is still time for a twist
and through the generations the Germans
have been the masters of holding their
Nerf
Iniesta
[Applause]
it's a rather forlorn looking Bastian
Schweinsteiger who's conceded this throw
in Spain's way there's no rush no hurry
now
they know they're on the brink
let's sit and watch Thomas Muller you
can only speculate as to how much he's
been missed
Gomez looking to play it through but
over here
you see is just stealing the nerve of
his Defenders
before belatedly taking hold of it and
wasting a few more seconds
[Applause]
90 seconds to go
but Germany still have a chance Lam
leading by example
here's herzl
blocked by Iniesta
Lam again it's drilling it here
motorcycle was up there didn't leap
Schweinsteiger
and PK assuredly comes away
but still not completely away
now Puyol
you're carried as far as he can and look
as far downfield with a clearance
they're going to make another change
here just to waste a few more seconds
it's Carlos marcheida who's coming on
shabby Alonso
who is going to be sacrificed for the
cause of Defense here
well he'll hardly complain taking his
time as he walks away Chevy Alonso and
Carlos marchina
another of those big Central Defenders
takes up his position
we're into the final 20 seconds puyo
with a header
Spain within touching distance now
Captiva hits it long
Torres on The Chase
[Applause]
Germany maybe still time for one final
fling
Spanish bench you're urging the referee
to blow his whistle
while cheetah heads it away
still not finished Ozil puts it in
cleared Away by Ramos and that might be
enough he's desperate to keep it in it
is
this Spanish Side Oh The History Boys
they've finally done it
Spain are in a World Cup final for the
very first time ever
and after all those Decades of promise
it is finally fulfilled
they have crowned their way past the
Germans as they did pass Paraguay and
Portugal
and Spain are in a World Cup final
Germany are out
the Heartbreak
of Schweinsteiger will be shared by his
Nation
but Carlos Puyol the hero of Spain has
steered his side through
it was tight and tense for an awful long
time
but it is Spain a health enough
and it is they who play Holland in the
final
they have beaten Germany by one goal to
nil